How about a ride,
mister?
Jennifer.
Oh, man, are you a sight
for sore eyes!
Let me look at you.
Marty, you're acting
like you haven't
seen me in a week.
I haven't.
Are you okay?
Is everything all right?
Oh, yeah.
Everything's great.
(EXPLOSIVE CRASHING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Marty!
You've got to come
back with me!
Where?
Back to the future.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing, Doc?
I need fuel.
Go ahead. Quick!
Get in the car.
No, no, no. Look, Doc,
I just got here, okay?
Jennifer's here.
We're gonna take
the new truck for a spin.
Well, bring her along.
This concerns her, too.
Wait a minute, Doc.
What are you
talking about?
What happens to us
in the future?
What, do we become assholes
or something?
No, no, no.
You and Jennifer
both turn out fine.
It's your kids, Marty.
Something has
got to be done
about your kids.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey, Doc, we better back up.
We don't have enough
road to get up to 88.
Roads? Where we're going,
we don't need roads.
Say, Marty!
Marty!
Marty, I wanted to show
you these new matchbooks
for my auto detailing
I had printed up.
A flying DeLorean?
What the hell
is going on here?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(HORN BLARING)
What the hell
was that?
Taxicab.
What do you mean a "taxicab"?
I thought we were flying.
Precisely.
All right, Doc.
What's going on, huh?
Where are we?
When are we?
We're descending
toward Hill Valley,
California,
at 4:29 p.m. On Wednesday,
October 21, 2015.
2015?
You mean
we're in the future.
Future.
Marty, what do you mean?
How can we be
in the future?
Jennifer...
I don't know how
to tell you this,
but you're
in a time machine.
JENNIFER: And this is
the year 2015?
October 21, 2015.
God, so, like,
you weren't kidding.
Marty, we can
actually see our future.
Doc, now, you said
we were married, right?
(HESITATING) Yeah...
Yeah?
Was it a big wedding?
Marty, we're gonna be able
to see our wedding.
Wow.
I'm gonna be able to
see my wedding dress.
Wow.
God, I wonder
where we live.
I bet it's a big house
with lots of kids.
How many kids...
(DEVICE WHINING)
Doc! What the hell
are you doing?
Relax, Marty.
It's just a sleep-inducing
alpha rhythm generator.
She was asking
too many questions,
and no one should
know too much
about their future.
This way
when she wakes up,
she'll think it
was all a dream.
Then what did
you bring her for?
I had to do something.
She saw the time machine.
I couldn't just leave her
there with that information.
Don't worry. She's not
essential to my plan.
Well, you're the doc,
Doc.
Here's our exit.
First, you've
gotta get out
and change clothes.
Right now?
It's pouring rain.
Wait five more seconds.
Right on the tick.
Amazing.
Absolutely amazing.
Too bad the post office
isn't as efficient as
the weather service.
Excuse the disguise,
Marty,
but I was afraid you
wouldn't recognize me.
I went to
a rejuvenation clinic
and got
an all-natural overhaul.
They took out some wrinkles,
did a hair repair,
changed the blood,
added a good 30 or
40 years to my life.
They also replaced
my spleen and colon.
What do you think?
You look great, Doc.
The future.
Unbelievable.
I gotta
check this out, Doc.
All in good time, Marty.
We're on a tight
schedule here.
Tell me about my future.
I mean, I know I make it big.
But what? Do I become,
like, a rich rock star?
Please, Marty, no one
should know too much
about their own destiny.
Right. Right.
I am rich, though, right?
Marty, please,
take off your shirt.
Put on the jacket
and the shoes.
Got a mission
to accomplish.
Ah-ha.
Precisely on schedule.
Power laces.
All right.
(WATCH ALARM BEEPING)
This thing doesn't fit.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Size-adjusting fit.
Pull out
your pants pockets.
All kids in the future
wear their pants inside out.
Put on this cap.
Perfect.
You're the spitting image
of your future son.
What?
Help me move
Jennifer over here.
So what's the deal?
Grab her feet.
All right.
Okay, now what?
In exactly two minutes,
you go around the corner
into the Cafe '80s.
Cafe '80s?
It's one of those
nostalgia places,
but not done very well.
Go in and order a Pepsi.
Here's a 50.
Then wait for
a guy named Griff.
Right. Griff.
Right.
Griff's going to
ask you about tonight.
Are you in or out?
Tell him you are out.
Whatever he says,
whatever happens,
say no,
you're not interested.
Okay.
Then leave,
come back here
and wait for me.
Don't talk to anyone,
don't touch anything,
don't do anything,
don't interact
with anyone
and try not to
look at anything.
I don't get it.
I thought you said
this had something
to do with my kids.
Look what happens
to your son.
My son?
God, he looks
just like me.
"Within two hours
of his arrest,
Martin McFly Jr
"was tried,
convicted and sentenced
"to 15 years in
a state penitentiary."
Within two hours?
The justice system works
swiftly in the future
now that they've
abolished all lawyers.
Oh, this is heavy.
It gets worse.
Next week, your daughter
attempts to break him
out of jail,
and she gets sent up
for 20 years.
My daughter.
Wait a minute.
I have a daughter?
You see? This one event
starts a chain reaction
that completely destroys
your entire family.
(EXCLAIMS)
Hey, Doc, this date...
This is tomorrow's newspaper.
Precisely, I already
went further ahead
into time
to see
what else happens.
I backtracked everything
to this one event.
That's why
we're here today,
to prevent this incident
from ever happening.
(BEEPING)
Damn! I'm late!
Wait a minute.
Where you going now?
To intercept
the real Marty Jr.
You're taking his place.
Around the corner
at the Cafe '80s.
Guy named Griff.
Just say no!
Hey, what about Jennifer?
We're not just gonna
leave her here.
Don't worry,
she'll be safe.
It'll just be
for a few minutes.
And, Marty,
be careful around
that Griff character.
He's got
a few short circuits
in his bionic implants.
MARTY: The future.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Welcome to Texaco.
You can trust your car
to the system with the star.
Checking oil.
Checking landing gear.
(JAWS THEME PLAYING)
(SCREAMING)
The shark
still looks fake.
(MUSIC BLARING)
Hi, friends.
Goldie Wilson III
for Wilson Hover
Conversion Systems.
You know, when my grandpa
was mayor of Hill Valley,
he had to worry
about traffic problems.
But now, you don't have
to worry about traffic.
I'll hover-convert
your old road car
into a skyway flier
for only $39,999.95.
So come on down and see me,
Goldie Wilson III,
at any one of our 29
convenient locations.
Remember,
keep 'em flying.
('80S POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
It's got a hot salsa,
avocados,
cilantro mixed
with your choice
of beans,
chicken, beef or pork.
Waiter. Waiter.
(WHIRRING)
Welcome to the Cafe '80s,
where it's always
morning in America,
even in the afternoon.
(LAUGHING)
Our special today is
mesquite-grilled sushi.
You must have
the hostage special!
Cajun style.
(DISTORTED)
You must have
the hostage special!
Hey, hey, hey, guys!
Hey, hey, guys!
All I want is a Pepsi.
Hey, McFly!
Yeah.
I've seen you around.
You're Marty McFly's kid,
aren't you?
Biff?
You're Marty Jr.
Tough break, kid.
Must be rough
being named after
a complete butthead.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Hello? Hello?
Anybody home?
Hey. Hey.
Think, McFly, think!
Your old man?
Mr. Loser?
What?
That's right.
Loser with a capital "L."
Look, I happen to know
George McFly is
no longer a loser.
No, I'm not talking
about George McFly.
I'm talking
about his kid.
Your old man,
Marty McFly Sr.,
the man who
took his life
and flushed it
completely down the toilet.
I did?
(STUTTERING) I mean...
I mean, he did?
Hey, Gramps,
I told you two coats
of wax on my car,
not just one!
Hey, hey, I just put
the second coat on
last week.
Yeah?
With your eyes closed?
Are you two related?
Hello? Hello?
Anybody home?
What do you think,
Griff just calls me
"Grandpa" for his health?
He's Griff?
Gramps!
What the hell
am I paying you for?
Hey, kid, say hello
to your grandma for me.
Get out here, Gramps.
OLDEST BIFF:
Hey, take it easy!
And, McFly,
don't go anywhere!
You're next!
BOY: This is a video game.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON VIDEO GAME)
I got it working.
My dad taught me
about these.
MARTY: It is Wild Gunman.
How do you play
this thing?
I'll show you, kid.
I'm a crack shot at this.
BOY: You mean you have
to use your hands?
That's like
a baby's toy.
Baby's toy?
Pepsi Perfect.
Damn!
Pepsi.
GRIFF: Hey, McFly!
I thought I told you
to stay in here!
Griff. Guys,
how's it going?
McFly!
Yeah?
What?
Your shoe's unvelked.
(GRIFF LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING SHEEPISHLY)
So, McFly, have you
made a decision about
tonight's opportunity?
Yeah, Griff. You know,
I was thinking about it.
I'm not sure,
because I just think,
you know,
it might be a little
bit dangerous, so...
What's wrong, McFly?
(WHIMPERING)
You got no scrote?
(GROANING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
He's a complete wimp.
What's it gonna be, McFly?
Are you in or out?
I just... I'm not sure
that I should.
You know, because I think
that I should discuss it
with my father.
Your father?
Wrong answer, McFly!
You lose!
(SCREAMING)
Okay, Griff, I'll do it.
I'll do it, buddy.
Whatever you say.
Stay down and shut up.
Keep pedaling,
you two!
Now, let's hear
the right answer.
Well!
Since when did you become
the physical type?
The answer's no, Griff.
No?
Yeah. What are you,
deaf and stupid?
I said no!
What's wrong, McFly?
Chicken?
(SYNTHESIZED CLUCKING)
What did you
call me, Griff?
Chicken, McFly!
Nobody calls me
chicken.
(SCREAMING)
(ELECTRICITY SURGING)
(GROANING)
('80S POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(DEVICE WHIRRING)
All right, punk!
Hey, look!
(ALL GROANING)
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Stop! Little girl,
little girl. Stop.
Hey.
Look,
I need to borrow
your Hoverboard.
Where is he?
Here.
There!
He's on a Hoverboard.
Get the boards!
GIRL: Get McFly!
(SCREAMING)
Get him!
Yeah!
Yeah, we got him!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
There's something
very familiar
about all this.
(GRUNTING)
Hey, McFly, you bojo!
Those boards
don't work on water!
Unless you've
got power!
(LAUGHING)
(PANTING)
Hook on!
Batter up!
(SCREAMING)
Holy shit!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Buttheads.
(SIREN WAILING)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Drying mode on.
Jacket drying.
(CONFIRMATION BEEP)
Your jacket is now dry.
Hey, kid.
Hey, little girl, thanks.
Keep it.
I got a Pit Bull now.
Come on. Let's go.
MAN: Save the clock tower!
Hey, kid.
Throw in 100 bucks, will you,
and help save
the clock tower.
Sorry, no.
Come on, kid.
That's an important
historical landmark!
Look, some other time.
MAN: Lightning struck
that thing 60 years ago.
MARTY: Wait a minute.
Cubs win World Series.
Against Miami?
Yeah, it's something, huh?
Who would've thought?
100-1 shot!
I wish I could go back
to the beginning
of the season,
put some money
on the Cubs.
I just meant
that Miami...
What did you just say?
I said I wish I could
go back to the beginning
of the season.
Put some money
on the Cubbies!
Now this has
an interesting feature.
It has a dust jacket.
Books used to have these
to protect the covers.
Of course,
that was before they had
dust-repellent paper.
Ah.
And if you're
interested in dust,
we have a quaint
little piece
from the 1980s.
It's called a DustBuster.
I can't lose.
Marty! Marty! Up here!
(WHISTLES)
Hey, Doc,
what's going on?
Stand by.
I'll park over there.
MARTY: Yeah, all right.
Hey, right on time.
Flying DeLorean.
I haven't seen one
of those in 30 years.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Sorry. Excuse me.
Sorry.
(HORN HONKING)
Hey, I'm walking here!
I'm walking here!
What the hell?
Don't drive, trank,
low-res scuzzball!
Two of them?
I left him in a suspended
animation kennel.
Einstein never
knew I was gone!
(SIREN WAILING)
Marty! What in the name
of Sir Isaac H. Newton
happened here?
Oh, yeah, Doc, listen,
my kid showed up.
All hell broke loose.
Your kid?
Great Scott,
the sleep inducer.
I was afraid of this.
Because I used it
on Jennifer,
there wasn't
enough power left
to knock your son out
for a full hour. Damn!
Doc, Doc, Doc,
look at this!
It's changing.
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
I was framed!
Yes! Yes, of course!
Because this
Hoverboard incident
has now occurred,
Griff now goes to jail.
Therefore,
your son won't go
with him tonight,
and that robbery
will never take place.
Thus, history,
future history,
has now been altered,
and this is the proof!
Marty, we've succeeded,
not exactly as I planned,
but no matter.
Let's go get Jennifer
and go home!
Hi, Einie. Hi, buddy.
(WHIMPERING)
What's this?
It's a souvenir.
"50 years of
sports statistics."
Hardly recreational
reading material, Marty.
Well, hey, Doc,
what's the harm
in bringing back
a little info
on the future?
You know, maybe we could
place a couple bets.
Marty, I didn't
invent the time machine
for financial gain!
The intent here is
to gain a clearer
perception of humanity.
Where we've been,
where we're going,
the pitfalls and
the possibilities,
the perils and the promise.
Perhaps even an answer
to that universal question,
"Why?"
Hey, Doc,
I'm all for that.
What's wrong with making
a few bucks on the side?
I am going to put
this in the trash.
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
Great Scott!
McFly,
Jennifer Jane Parker,
3793 Oakhurst Street,
Hilldale, age 47.
Forty-seven?
That's a hell of
a good face-lift.
What the hell are
they doing, Doc?
They used her thumbprint
to assess her ID.
Since her thumbprint
never changes
over the years,
they simply assume
she's the Jennifer
of the future.
Well, we gotta stop them.
What are we gonna say?
That we're time travelers?
They'd have us committed.
She's clean.
That means
we take her home.
Home? To Hilldale?
Lt'll be dark
by the time
we get out there.
That's it.
They're taking her home
to your future home!
We'll arrive
shortly thereafter,
get her out of there
and go back to 1985.
You mean I'm gonna
see where I live?
I'm gonna see myself
as an old man?
No, no, no, Marty.
That could result in...
(GASPS) Great Scott!
Jennifer could
conceivably encounter
her future self!
The consequences of that
could be disastrous!
Doc, what do you mean?
I foresee
two possibilities.
One, coming face to face
with herself 30 years older
would put her into shock,
and she'd simply pass out,
or two,
the encounter could
create a time paradox,
the results of which could
cause a chain reaction
that would unravel
the very fabric of
the space-time continuum
and destroy
the entire universe!
Granted, that's
a worst-case scenario.
The destruction might,
in fact, be very localized,
limited to
merely our own galaxy.
Well, that's a relief.
Let's go. I sure hope
we find Jennifer
before she finds herself.
The skyway's jammed.
It's gonna take us
forever to get there.
And this stays here.
I didn't invent
the time machine
to win at gambling.
I invented a time machine
to travel through time!
I know. I know.
I know, Doc.
So, Doc Brown
invented a time machine.
Hilldale.
Nothing but a breeding
ground for tranks,
lobos and zipheads.
Yeah, they ought to tear
this whole place down.
(BEEPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Welcome home, Jennifer.
Whoa!
You all right?
Yeah.
You got a little tranked,
but I think you can walk.
Ma'am,
you should reprogram.
It's dangerous to
enter without lights on.
JENNIFER: Lights on?
Yes. Now, look.
Just take it easy
and you'll be fine.
And be careful
in the future.
The future?
Have a nice day,
Mrs. McFly.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Broadcasting beautiful views
24 hours a day,
you're tuned to
the Scenery Channel.
I'm in the future.
I get married in
the Chapel O Love?
MARLENE: Mom?
Mom, is that you?
I gotta get
out of here!
(DOOR BELL RINGING)
Mom!
Mom? Mom, is that you?
(DOOR OPENS)
Grandma Lorraine!
Sweetheart!
Hi!
What happened
to Grandpa?
Oh, he threw
his back out again.
How's Granddad's
little pumpkin?
How did you do that?
How did he do that?
Oh, out on the
golf course. (GROANS)
Are your folks home yet?
I brought pizza
for everyone.
Oh, who's going
to eat all that?
Oh, I will.
Damn this traffic!
Jennifer,
that is Old Jennifer,
usually gets home around now.
I hope we're
not too late.
What is it?
What's the matter, Doc?
For a moment,
I thought I saw a taxi
in my rear display.
I thought it was
following us. Weird.
OLDEST LORRAINE:
I can't believe this
window's still broken.
MARLENE: Well, when
the scenescreen repairman
called Daddy a chicken,
Daddy threw him
out of the house.
Now, we can't get
anybody to fix it.
Oh, look how
worn out this is.
Your father's
biggest problem, Marlene,
is that he loses
all self-control
when someone
calls him chicken.
How many times have
we heard it, George?
"Mom, I can't let them
think I'm chicken."
"Can't let them
You're right.
Well, you're right!
OLDEST LORRAINE:
About 30 years ago,
your father tried to
prove he wasn't chicken,
and he ended up in
an automobile accident.
MARLENE: Oh, you mean with
the Rolls-Royce?
Automobile accident.
All right, Einie,
let's find Jennifer.
I don't believe it.
I live in Hilldale?
This is great!
Way to go, McFly.
Marty, stay here.
Just change clothes.
If I need you,
I'll holler.
Come on, Doc, I wanna
check out my house.
We can't risk you running
into your older self.
Come on, Einie,
let's go.
Where's Jennifer?
Hilldale.
This is bitching.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
One, seven,
four point five zero.
That will be $174.50.
Here.
I'd be careful, old timer.
This is a rough neighborhood.
Where's my receipt?
Right here. Here it is.
PARROT: Hello. Hello.
How about a tip?
(PARROT LAUGHING)
That accident caused
a chain reaction
that sent Marty's life
straight down the tubes.
If not for that accident,
your father's life
would have turned out
very differently.
The man in the Rolls-Royce
wouldn't have
pressed charges,
Marty wouldn't
have broken his hand,
and he wouldn't have
given up on his music,
spent all those years
feeling sorry for himself.
Hey, Mom, nice pants.
I think the real reason
your mother married him
was because
she felt sorry for him.
"Mom"?
Such a sweet girl.
Art off.
OLDEST LORRAINE: I think
maybe she deserves...
Okay, I want channels
18, 24, 63, 109, 87
and the Weather Channel.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
The Weather Channel,
bringing you
the world's weather
24 hours a day.
(CHATTERING ON TV)
Weather conditions
remain the same...
All board-certified
implant surgeons...
With a minor warm front...
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Welcome home, Marty.
MARTY JR: Hey, hey, hey.
Dad's home.
That's right.
He's home.
Dad's home.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Lord of the manor.
Hello. Hello.
King of the castle.
Hello.
What the hell is this?
(BEEPS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Lithium mode on.
Yeah. That's better.
Damned kids.
AUTOMATED VOICE: The best...
Hey, Son.
Watching a little TV
for a change?
(BEEPING)
Son of a...
(ENGINE STARTING)
MARTY JR: Hey, pizza.
I'm hungry.
OLDER MARTY: All right.
Just wait your turn.
MARTY JR: Grandma,
when it's ready,
could you just
shove it in my mouth?
(LAUGHING HUMOROUSLY)
OLDER MARTY:
Don't you be a smartass.
MARTY JR: Oh, great!
The Atrocity Channel.
Hydrate level 4, please.
(GURGLING)
(BELL DINGS)
Mmm.
MARTY JR: Is it ready?
OLDEST LORRAINE:
Here you go.
OLDER MARTY:
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
Mom, you sure
can hydrate a pizza.
I'm sorry. I missed
that whole thing.
OLDEST LORRAINE: Well, I'm
just worried about Jennifer.
Why isn't she home yet?
I'm not sure
where Jennifer is, Mom.
She should have
been home hours ago.
I'm having a hard time
keeping track of
her these days.
Hey, fruit.
Fruit, please. Thank you.
She's in one of
those moods, I guess.
I don't know.
OLDEST LORRAINE:
Aren't you and Jennifer
getting along?
Oh, yeah.
Great, Mom.
We're more like
a couple of teenagers,
you know.
(PHONE RINGING)
Dad, telephone.
It's Needles.
Dad, it's for you.
All right. Well,
I'll take that in the den.
Excuse me.
Retract.
Hello.
I'm in here, please.
Hey, the big M.
How's it hanging, McFly?
Hey, Needles.
Needles?
So, did you take look
at that little business
proposal of mine?
OLDER MARTY:
I don't know, Needles.
NEEDLES: What are
you afraid of?
If this thing works,
it'll solve all your
financial problems.
And if it
doesn't work, Needles,
I could get fired.
It's illegal.
I mean, what if the Jits
is monitoring, huh?
The Jits will
never find out.
Oh, God.
Come on. Stick your
card in the slot,
and I'll handle it.
Unless you want
everyone in the division
to think you're chicken.
Nobody calls me chicken,
Needles.
Nobody!
NEEDLES: All right.
Prove it.
All right.
All right, Needles.
(SCOFFS)
Here's my card.
Scan it. I'm in.
Thanks, McFly.
I'll see you at
the plant tomorrow.
(AUTOMATED VOICE READING)
Chicken.
McFly!
(GREETING IN JAPANESE)
McFly, I was monitoring
that scan you
just interfaced.
You are terminated!
Terminated. No!
No! It wasn't
my fault, sir.
It was Needles.
Needles was
behind the whole thing.
And you cooperated.
No, I didn't.
It was a sting operation.
It was illegal.
I was setting him up.
And you knew.
McFly, read my fax!
No! Please, no.
I cannot be fired.
I'm fired.
(EXCLAIMS IN DISAPPOINTMENT)
(WHIRRING)
Oh, this is heavy.
What am I going
to tell Jennifer?
Jennifer. Jennifer.
Oh, Doc, am I glad
to see you.
Go out the front door.
I'll meet you there.
But it doesn't open.
There's no doorknob.
Press your thumb
to the plate.
What plate?
(DOOR OPENS)
Marty, what does
this fax mean?
Oh, Mom, it's a joke,
an office joke.
Kind of a joke fax.
OLDEST LORRAINE:
Marty, I heard you yelling.
Mom, Mom, Mom,
calm down.
I wasn't yelling.
Needles and I were
just kind of joking.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Welcome home, Jennifer.
OLDEST LORRAINE: Marty,
have you lost your job?
Lost my job, Mom?
Get out of town.
Look, you know...
(BOTH GASPING)
I'm young!
I'm old!
Marty! Marty!
Marty, come quick!
Quick!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
She encountered
her older self
and went into shock,
just as I predicted.
She'll be fine.
Let's get her back
to 1985,
and then I'm gonna destroy
the time machine.
Destroy it?
What about that
stuff about humanity,
where we're going
and why?
The risks
are just too great,
as this incident proves.
And I was
behaving responsibly.
You can imagine
the danger
if the time machine
were to fall
into the wrong hands.
(GROANING)
My only regret is that
I'll never get a chance
to visit my favorite
historical era,
the Old West.
But time traveling
is just too dangerous.
Better that I devote
myself to studying
the other great mystery
of the universe,
women.
Marty, Einie,
brace yourselves for
temporal displacement.
(ENGINE HUMMING)
Did we make it?
Are we back?
(SCREAMING)
We're back.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Let's put her
in the swing.
Then I'll take you home,
and you can come back
in your truck
and wake her.
When she awakens here
in her own house
and it's dark,
you should be
able to convince her
that it was all a dream.
Wait a minute.
We're just gonna
leave her here
on the porch?
The disorientation
will help convince her
that it was all a dream.
How long do you think
she's gonna be out?
I'm not quite sure.
She received quite
a shock.
Could be for
a few minutes.
Most probably,
a couple of hours.
You better
bring smelling salts
back with you.
You're the doc, Doc.
All right. Come on.
Let's go, Einie.
(EINSTEIN WHIMPERING)
Don't worry.
She'll be fine.
I don't remember bars
being on these windows.
(DOGS GROWLING)
If you need me,
I'll be back at my lab
dismantling this thing.
Right.
What the hell?
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
Hey. Hey, wait.
Wait a minute.
(STUTTERING) What are
you doing in my room?
Help! Rape! Mom!
Okay. Okay.
Dad, help!
Freeze, sucker!
He jumped me!
Hey, it's okay.
I don't want any trouble.
He came through
the window!
You got trouble now,
you piece of trash.
What are you doing in here
with my daughter?
Hey, listen, I'm just
in the wrong house.
You got that right,
you little son of a...
Hey, look,
I made a mistake.
Damn right you
made a mistake!
BOY: Kill him!
I'm gonna tear
your ass up!
That's right.
You keep running, sucker!
And you tell
that realty company
that I ain't selling!
You hear?
We ain't gonna
be terrorized!
(DOGS HOWLING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
This has gotta
be the wrong year.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
1985?
It can't be.
(GUN COCKING)
STRICKLAND: Drop it.
So you're the son of
a bitch who's been
stealing my newspapers.
Mr. Strickland.
It's me, sir.
It's Marty.
Who?
It's Marty McFly.
Marty McFly.
Don't you know me, sir?
From school, sir.
I've never seen you
before in my life,
but you look to
me like a slacker.
Yeah, that's right.
That's right.
I am a slacker.
Don't you remember?
You gave me detention
last week.
Last week?
The school burned
down six years ago.
Now, you got
exactly three seconds
to get off my porch
with your nuts intact.
One.
Please, Mr. Strickland,
I just want to know
what the hell's
going on here.
Two.
(SCREAMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey, Strickland!
BOY: Yeah!
(EXCLAIMING)
Eat lead, slackers!
(SCREAMING)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Watch where you're going,
crazy drunk pedestrian.
Red.
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to
the Biff Tannen Museum.
Dedicated to Hill Valley's
number one citizen
and America's
greatest living folk hero,
the one and only
Biff Tannen.
Of course,
we've all heard the legend,
but who is the man?
Inside, you will learn
how Biff Tannen became
one of the richest
and most powerful men
in America.
Learn the amazing history
of the Tannen family,
starting with his
great-grandfather,
Buford "Mad Dog" Tannen,
fastest gun in the West.
See Biff's
humble beginnings
and how a trip
to the racetrack
on his 21 st birthday
made him a millionaire
overnight.
(BELL RINGING)
Share in the excitement
of a fabulous winning streak
that earned him the nickname
"The Luckiest Man on Earth."
Learn how Biff parlayed
that lucky winning streak
into the vast empire
called Biffco.
Discover how in 1979,
Biff successfully lobbied
to legalize gambling
and turned Hill Valley's
dilapidated courthouse
into a beautiful
casino hotel.
I just want
to say one thing.
God bless America!
MAN: Meet the women
who shared in his passion
as he searched
for true love,
and relive
Biff's happiest moment
as, in 1973, he realized
his life-long romantic dream
by marrying his
high school sweetheart,
Lorraine Baines McFly.
REPORTER: How's it feel,
Mr. Tannen?
Third time's
the charm.
No! No!
Hey, you're coming
with us upstairs.
Let me go.
Look, sonny, we can
do this the easy way
or the hard way.
MAN: The easy way.
Mom? Mom, is that you?
OLDER LORRAINE:
Just relax, Marty.
You've been asleep
for almost two hours.
I had a horrible nightmare.
It was terrible.
Well, you're safe
and sound now,
back on the good
old 27th floor.
Twenty-seventh floor!
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Mom?
Mom, that can't be you.
Well, yes,
it's me, Marty.
Are you all right?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
It's just that you're
so... You're so
big.
Oh. Everything's
gonna be fine, Marty.
Are you hungry?
I can call room service.
(GASPS)
Room service?
OLDER BIFF: Lorraine!
Oh, my God.
It's your father.
My father?
You're supposed to
be in Switzerland,
you little son of a bitch!
My father!
Did you get kicked out
of another boarding school?
Damn it, Lorraine.
Do you know how much
perfectly good dough
I've blown on this
no-good kid of yours, huh?
On all three of them?
What the hell
do you care?
We can afford it.
The least we can do
with all that money
is provide a better life
for our children.
Hold on one second.
Let's get this straight.
Marty is your kid,
not mine.
And all the money
in the world
wouldn't do jack shit
for that lazy bum.
Stop it, Biff.
Just stop it.
Look at him.
He's a butthead,
just like his old man was.
Don't you dare speak
that way about George.
You're not even
half the man he was.
(GRUNTS)
You son of a bitch!
Hey.
(GROANING)
OLDER BIFF: Always
the little hothead, huh?
You wanna
take a poke at me?
(MAN LAUGHING)
Damn it, Biff.
That's it. I'm leaving.
(LAUGHS MOCKINGLY)
So go ahead. But think
about this, Lorraine!
Who's gonna pay for
all your clothes, huh?
And your jewelry
and your liquor?
Who's gonna pay for
your cosmetic surgery,
Lorraine?
You were the one
who wanted me to
get these things.
If you want them back,
you can have them.
Look, Lorraine.
You walk out that door,
and I won't
only cut off you.
I'll cut off your kids.
You wouldn't.
Wouldn't I?
First your daughter,
Linda.
I'll cancel all
her credit cards.
She can settle her
debts with the bank
all by herself.
Your idiot son, Dave.
I'll get his
probation revoked.
And as for Marty.
Well, maybe you'd like
to have all three
of your kids behind bars,
just like
your brother Joey.
One big, happy,
jailbird family.
All right, Biff.
You win. I'll stay.
As for you, I'll be
back up here in an hour,
so you better not be.
He was right,
and I was wrong.
Mom!
Mom,
what are you saying?
You're actually
defending him.
I had it coming.
He's my husband,
and he takes care
of all of us,
and he deserves
our respect.
(YELLING) Respect?
Your husband!
How could he
be your husband?
How could you
leave Dad for him?
Leave Dad?
Marty, are you
feeling all right?
No. No, I'm not
feeling all right!
I don't understand
one damn thing that's
going on around here,
and why nobody can
give me a simple,
straight answer.
Oh, they must have
hit you over the head
hard this time.
Mom, I just want
to know one thing.
Where's my father?
Where's George McFly?
Marty, George,
your father
is in the same place
he's been for
the past 12 years.
Oak Park Cemetery.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
No.
No! This can't
be happening!
"March 15, 1973."
No! Please, God, no!
No, please, God.
Please, God, no.
This can't be happening.
This can't be...
I'm afraid it is
happening, Marty.
All of it.
Doc!
When I learned
about your father,
I figured
you'd come here.
(WIND HOWLING)
Then you know
what happened to him?
Do you know
what happened
March 15, 1973?
Yes, Marty. I know.
DOC: I went
to the public library
to try to make sense
out of all the madness.
The place was
boarded up, shut down,
so I broke in and
borrowed some newspapers.
I don't get it, Doc.
I mean, how can all
this be happening?
It's like we're in
hell or something.
No, it's Hill Valley.
Although, I can't imagine
hell being much worse.
(EINSTEIN WHIMPERING)
Oh, Einie.
I'm sorry, boy.
The lab is an awful,
awful, awful, awful mess.
Attaboy.
Obviously,
the time continuum
has been disrupted,
creating this new
temporal event sequence
resulting in this
alternate reality.
English, Doc.
Here, here, here.
Let me illustrate.
Imagine that this line
represents time.
Here's the present, 1985,
the future and the past.
Prior to
this point in time,
somewhere in the past,
the timeline skewed
into this tangent
creating
an alternate 1985.
Alternate to you,
me and Einstein,
but reality for
everyone else.
Recognize this?
It's the bag
the sports book came in.
I know,
because the receipt
was still inside.
I found them in
the time machine
along with this.
It's the top
of Biff's cane.
I mean,
Old Biff from the future.
Correct. It was
in the time machine
because Biff was
with the sports almanac.
Holy shit.
You see,
while we were
in the future,
Biff got
the sports book,
stole the time machine,
went back in time,
and gave the book to himself
at some point in the past.
Look. It says right here
that Biff made
his first million
betting on a horse race
in 1958.
He wasn't just lucky.
He knew because he had
all the race results
in the sports almanac.
That's how he made
his entire fortune.
Look at his pocket
with a magnifying glass.
The almanac.
Son of a bitch
stole my idea.
He must have been
listening when I...
It's my fault.
The whole thing
is my fault.
If I hadn't bought
that damn book,
none of this would
have ever happened.
Well, it's all
in the past.
You mean the future?
Whatever.
It demonstrates precisely
how time travel
can be misused
and why the time machine
must be destroyed
after we straighten
all of this out.
Right. So we go
back to the future,
and we stop Biff
from stealing
the time machine.
We can't,
because if we travel
into the future from
this point in time,
it will be the future
of this reality,
in which Biff is
corrupt and powerful
and married
to your mother
and in which this
has happened to me.
(WHIMPERING)
No. Our only chance
to repair the present
is in the past
at the point where
the timeline skewed
into this tangent.
In order to put
the universe back
as we remember it
and get back
to our reality,
we have to find
out the exact date
and the specific
circumstances
of how, where
and when Young Biff
got his hands on
that sports almanac.
I'll ask him.
Bulletproof vest!
(LAUGHS) Great flick!
Great frigging flick!
The guy is brilliant.
Hey, what the hell's
going...
(GIRLS SCREAMING)
Hey! What the hell
are you doing in here?
Party's over, Biff.
Sorry, ladies.
How did you get past
my security downstairs?
There's a little matter
we need to talk about.
Yeah. Money, right?
Well, forget it.
No. Not money.
Gray's Sports Almanac.
You heard him, girls.
Party's over.
Start talking, kid.
What else you know
about that book?
First, you tell me
how you got it.
How, where and when.
(SCOFFS)
All right.
Take a seat.
Sit down!
November 12, 1955.
That was when.
That was the date
I went back...
That was the date of
the famous Hill Valley
lightning storm.
You know your history.
Very good.
I'll never forget
that Saturday.
I'd just picked
my car up from the shop,
'cause I'd rolled it
in a drag race
a few days earlier.
I thought you crashed
into a manure truck.
How do you know
about that?
My father told me
about it.
Your father?
Before he died.
Yeah. Right.
So there I was,
minding my own business.
This crazy old codger
with a cane shows up.
He says he's my
distant relative.
I don't see
any resemblance.
So he says,
"How would you
like to be rich?"
So I said, "Sure."
So he lays
this book on me.
He says this book
will tell me the outcome
of every sporting event
till the end of the century.
All I have to do is
bet on the winner,
and I'll never lose.
So I said,
"What's the catch?"
He says, "No catch.
Just keep it a secret."
(SIGHS)
After that,
he disappeared.
I never saw him again.
Oh, and he told me
one more thing.
He said,
"Someday a crazy,
wild-eyed scientist,
"or a kid may show up
asking about that book.
"And if that
ever happens..."
(CHUCKLES)
Funny. I never
thought it would be you.
Yeah, well, Biff,
you're forgetting
one thing.
What the hell is that?
You're dead,
you little son of a bitch!
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Hey, there he is!
Hey, hey!
(THUGS YELLING)
Oh, yeah!
Go ahead, kid. Jump.
A suicide will
be nice and neat.
What if I don't?
Lead poisoning.
What about
the police, Biff?
They're gonna
match up the bullet
with that gun.
Kid, I own the police.
Besides,
they couldn't match up
the bullet that
killed your old man.
You son of a...
I suppose it's
poetic justice.
Two McFlys
with the same gun.
Idiot.
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
What the hell?
(GROANS)
Nice shot, Doc!
You're not
gonna believe this.
We gotta
go back to 1955.
I don't believe it.
MARTY: That's right, Doc.
November 12, 1955.
Unbelievable that
Old Biff could've chosen
that particular date.
It could mean that
that point in time
inherently contains
some sort of
cosmic significance,
almost as if it were
the temporal junction point
for the entire
space-time continuum.
On the other hand,
it could just be
an amazing coincidence.
(BEEPING)
Damn!
Got to fix that thing.
All right.
Time circuits on.
What do you mean,
time circuits on?
Doc, we're not
going back now.
Yep.
Doc, what about Jennifer?
What about Einstein?
We can't just
leave them here.
Don't worry, Marty.
Assuming we succeed
in our mission,
this alternate 1985
will be changed back
into the real 1985,
instantaneously transforming
around Jennifer and Einie.
Jennifer and Einie
will be fine,
and they will have
absolutely no memory
of this horrible place.
Doc.
What if we don't succeed?
We must succeed.
This is heavy, Doc.
I mean, it's like I was
just here yesterday.
You were here
yesterday, Marty.
You were.
Amazing, isn't it?
All right,
sunrise should be
in about 22 minutes.
You go into town.
Track down Young Biff
and tail him.
Sometime today,
Old Biff will show up
to give Young Biff
the almanac.
Above all you,
must not interfere
with that event.
We must let Old Biff
believe he's succeeded,
so that he'll leave 1955
and bring the DeLorean
back to the future.
Right.
Once Old Biff is gone,
grab the almanac
any way that you can.
Remember,
both of our futures
depend on this.
You don't have to
remind me of that, Doc.
Here's some binoculars
and a walkie-talkie
so we can keep in contact.
I'll stay here and
try to repair the short
in the time circuit.
That way, we don't
risk anyone else
stealing the time machine,
and I won't risk
accidentally running
into my other self.
Other self?
Yes. There are now
two of me here,
and there are
two of you here.
The other me is
the Dr. Emmett Brown
from 1955,
the younger me that
helps the other you
get back to 1985.
Remember the lightning bolt
at the clock tower?
Yeah.
That event doesn't
happen until tonight,
so you must be
very careful not to run
into your other self.
Let me give you
some money.
(MARTY WHISTLES)
I have to be prepared
for all monetary
possibilities.
Get yourself
some '50s clothes.
Check, Doc.
Something inconspicuous.
Doc. Come in, Doc.
This is Marty. Over.
DOC ON RADIO:
Roger, Marty. This is Doc.
Are you there?
Yeah, Doc.
I'm at the address.
It's the only Tannen
in the book,
but I don't think
this is Biff's house.
It looks like some
old lady lives here.
WOMAN: Biff!
Yeah.
Where are you
going, Biff?
I'm going to get
my car, Grandma.
When are you
coming back?
My feet hurt,
and I want you to rub
my toes some more.
Shut up,
you old bag.
KIDS: Give us
our ball back.
What ball?
That ball!
What ball are
you talking about?
KIDS: Give us our ball!
What ball?
Biff!
Is this your ball?
KIDS: Yeah!
Is it your ball?
You want it back?
KIDS: Yeah.
Go get it.
(LAUGHING)
Doc, it is Biff's house.
I'm on him. Over.
Hey.
Looking good, Terry.
Hey, Biff, she's all
fixed up just like new,
but I couldn't
get her started.
You got some
kind of kill switch
on this thing?
No, you just gotta
have the right touch.
Nobody can start
this car but me.
Yeah, the bill
comes to $302.57.
300 bucks?
300 bucks for
a couple of dents?
No, hey,
that's bullshit, Terry.
No, Biff,
it was horse shit.
The whole car
was full of it.
(CHUCKLES)
We had to pay
Old Man Jones 80 bucks
to haul it away.
BIFF: Old Man Jones
probably resold it, too.
Now I ought to get
something for that.
You want
something for it?
We'll go inside.
You can call
Old Man Jones.
If he wants to
give you a refund...
It's 300 bucks, Terry.
If I catch the guy
that caused this,
I'll break his neck.
The manure.
I remember that.
Four cans of Valvoline
is fair, Biff.
Four cans
for a $300 job?
I couldn't even
have lunch in the shop.
Makes me nauseous.
I should get
a case of oil
out of you for
a 300 buck job.
You've been inside.
It smells worse
than the bathroom
at a gas station.
(GROANS)
You robbed me again,
Terry. Yeah, yeah.
The smell's never
gonna go away, Biff.
Never gonna go away.
Last time I do you
a favor. Last time.
Thanks a lot.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Let me see.
(EXCLAIMS)
BABS: It's perfect,
Lorraine.
LORRAINE:
Oh, look at it!
You're going to
look so good!
You're going
to look...
Well, lookey
what we have here.
Hey, nice dress,
Lorraine.
Although,
I think you'd look better
wearing nothing at all.
Biff, why don't
you take a long walk
off a short pier?
BIFF: Hey, listen, Lorraine.
There's that dance at
school tonight, right.
Now that
my car's all fixed,
I figure
I'd cut you a break
and give you
the honor of going
with the best-looking
guy in school.
Yeah, well, I'm busy.
Yeah, doing what?
Washing my hair.
That's about as funny
as a screen door
on a battleship.
Screen door on
a submarine, you dork.
Look, Biff, somebody
already asked me
to the dance.
Who? That bug
George McFly?
I'm going with
Calvin Klein, okay?
Calvin Klein?
No, it's not okay.
You're going
with me, understand?
Get your cooties
off me!
When are you gonna
get it through your
thick skull, Lorraine?
You're my girl.
Biff Tannen,
I wouldn't be your girl
even if you had
a million dollars!
(GROANS)
Yes, you will!
It's you and me,
Lorraine.
(HORN HONKING)
Watch it!
It's meant to be.
I'm going to marry
you someday, Lorraine.
Someday you'll
be my wife!
You always did
have a way with women.
Get the hell out
of my car, old man.
You want to marry
that girl, Biff?
I can help
make it happen.
Oh, yeah? Who are you,
Miss Lonely-Hearts?
Just get in the car,
butthead.
(STARTS ENGINE)
Who are you calling
butthead, butthead?
How do you know
how to do that?
Nobody can start
this car but me.
Just get in the car, Tannen.
Today's your lucky day.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey! Hey!
Hey, watch where you're
driving, old man.
If you dent this car,
I'll kill you.
(EXCLAIMING)
This cost me
300 bucks!
Would you shut up
about the car?
Hey, and another thing.
How do you know
where I live?
Let's just say
we're related, Biff.
And that being the case,
I got a little present
for you.
Something that'll
make you rich.
You want to be rich,
don't you?
Oh, yeah. Sure. Right.
That's rich. (LAUGHS)
You're going
to make me rich?
You see this book?
This book tells
the future.
Tells the results of
every major sports event
till the end
of the century.
Football, baseball,
horse races, boxing.
The information in here
is worth millions,
and I'm giving it to you.
Well, that's very nice.
Thank you very much.
Now, why don't
you make like a tree
and get out of here?
It's leave, you idiot.
Make like a tree and leave.
You sound like a damn fool
when you say it wrong.
All right, then,
leave and take
your book with you.
Don't you get it?
You could make a fortune
with this book.
Let me show you.
(STATIC)
MAN ON RADIO:
UCLA trails 17-16.
It's 4th and 11
with only 18 seconds
left of this game.
I'd say it's
all over for UCLA.
Bet you a million bucks
UCLA wins it 19-17.
What are you,
deaf, old man?
He just said it was over.
You lost.
Oh, yeah?
(VOLUME INCREASING)
Here comes Decker
with the kick.
It's up.
It looks good, folks!
It looks very good.
Field goal!
UCLA wins 19-17.
Listen to that
Coliseum crowd go wild.
Jim Decker...
All right, pops.
What's the gag?
How did you know
what the score
was gonna be?
I told you.
It's in this book.
All you gotta do is
bet on the winner,
and you'll never lose.
All right.
I'll take a look at it.
OLDEST BIFF:
You damn fool!
Never, never leave
this book laying around.
Don't you have a safe?
No, you don't have a safe.
Get a safe.
Keep it locked up.
And until then,
keep it on you
like this.
Hey, what are you doing?
And don't tell
anybody about it,
either.
And there's
one more thing.
One day,
a kid or a crazy,
wild-eyed old man
who claims to
be a scientist
is going to come around
asking about this...
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
If that ever happens...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm trapped. Doc.
Doc, come in, Doc.
Marty, what's the report?
Biff's gone.
He's got the book.
The old man's gone, too.
I'm locked in Biff's garage.
You gotta fly
the DeLorean over here
and get me
the hell out of here.
The address is
1809 Mason Street.
I can't take the DeLorean
out in the daylight,
but don't worry, Marty.
Somehow I'll get
over there.
Doc, wait a minute.
Doc. Hey, Doc. Doc.
Perfect.
I told you, Grandma.
I'm going to the dance.
WOMAN:
When you coming home?
The dance.
BIFF: I'll get home
when I get home.
Don't forget to turn
off the garage light.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(BICYCLE BELL RINGING)
Marty. Marty!
Marty.
Marty, Marty. Damn!
Where is that kid?
(MUSIC PLAYING ON CAR STEREO)
Doc. Doc, come in.
Come in, Doc.
Marty! Marty, come in.
Doc.
(FEEDBACK)
Marty.
Oh, my...
Great Scott.
Oh, my God.
Doc, Doc, come in.
Marty,
what happened to you?
I went to Biff's house,
and you weren't there.
You must have
just missed me.
I'm in the back
of Biff's car.
He's on his way
to the Enchantment
Under the Sea dance.
Marty, listen,
we may have to abort
this entire plan.
It's getting
much too dangerous.
Don't worry.
The book is on
Biff's dashboard.
I'll grab it as soon
as we get to the school.
Marty, you must
be extremely careful
not to run into
your other self.
My other self?
Yes.
Remember, your mother is
at that exact same dance
with you. Yeah.
Right. This could
get heavy, Doc.
Heavy, heavy.
Marty, whatever happens,
you must not let
your other self see you!
The consequences
could be disastrous.
Excuse me, sir.
(GASPS)
Yes, you with the hat.
Who, me?
Yes.
Be a pal and hand me
a five-eighths inch wrench
out of that toolbox.
Five-eighths?
Don't you mean
three-quarters?
Why, you're right.
I presume you're
conducting some sort of
weather experiment.
That's right.
How did you know that?
I happen to have had
a little experience
in this area.
Yes, well, I'm hoping
to see some
lightning tonight.
Although, the weatherman
says there's not
gonna be any rain.
There's going to
be plenty of rain,
all right.
Wind, thunder,
lightning.
It's gonna be one
hell of a storm.
Well, thanks.
Nice talking to you.
Maybe we'll bump into
each other some time
again in the future.
Or in the past.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Doc, Doc! Come in!
(GIRLS EXCLAIMING)
BIFF: Where's that punk
Calvin Klein, anyway?
BOY: How am I
supposed to know, Biff?
I ain't his secretary.
(LAUGHING)
Well, go find him.
He caused 300 bucks
damage to my car,
and I owe him
a knuckle sandwich.
Get going!
Drink up, Biff.
Yeah, thanks.
Ain't you coming?
I'm reading.
(BOTTLE BREAKING)
Well, well, well,
Mr. Tannen.
How nice
to see you here.
Why, Mr. Strickland,
it's nice to see you, sir.
Is that liquor
I smell, Tannen?
(STUTTERING)
I wouldn't know.
I don't know what
liquor smells like,
'cause I'm too
young to drink it.
I see.
And what have we here?
Sports statistics,
interesting subject.
Homework, Tannen?
No, it ain't homework,
'cause I ain't at home.
(CHUCKLES)
You've got a real
attitude problem.
You know that, Tannen?
Just watch it.
Because one day,
I'll have you
right where I want you
in detention.
Slacker!
MARTY: Jesus,
you smoke, too?
LORRAINE: Marty, you're
beginning to sound
just like my mother.
Yeah, right.
When I have kids,
I'm going to let them
do anything they want.
Anything at all.
Yeah, I'd like to
have that in writing.
Yeah, me, too.
Marty,
why are you so nervous?
(DOOR CLOSES)
Yes!
No!
"Oh Là Là?"
(ANXIOUS GASPING)
Doc! Doc!
Hey, you.
Doc, come in!
DOC: Marty, what's up?
Doc! I'm in trouble.
I blew it.
Where's the book?
Biff must still
have it with him.
All I got is
the damn cover.
And where's Biff?
You're asking for it.
I don't know.
Don't you have any
idea where he is?
No! I mean, he could
be anywhere by now.
Marty, the entire
future depends on you
finding Biff and
getting that book back!
I know.
I just don't know where...
LORRAINE: Stop it!
Stop it, Biff.
You'll break his arm.
Stop it!
Of course!
I gotta go.
I got one chance!
My old man is
about to deck Biff!
Yes!
Talk about déjà vu.
Are you okay?
Okay, everybody,
let's back up now.
Let's back up.
Let's everybody
just back up
and give him
a little bit of room,
okay.
A little bit of air.
It's okay.
I know CPR. I know CPR.
Hey.
What's CPR?
You!
He's fine.
Hey, did you
just take his wallet?
He just took
that guy's wallet.
MARTY: Doc, success.
I got it.
Thank goodness.
Great, Marty.
As soon as I reload
the fusion generator,
I'll meet you on the roof
of the high school gym.
On the roof. 10-4.
Hey, it's him!
Hey, he's in disguise.
Guys, what's that?
Come on!
Let's get him!
Damn!
MARVIN: (SINGING)
Earth angel
Please be mine
My darling dear
Love you for all time
I'm just a fool
A fool in love
with you
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
All right!
Let's do another one.
Where did he go?
He just came in here!
MARTY: Something
that really cooks.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Look! How did he
get up on stage?
I don't know,
but when he gets down,
we're gonna nail him.
How the hell did
he change his
clothes so fast?
MARTY: All right,
it's an oldie
where I come from.
All right, guys, listen,
this is a blues riff in B.
Watch me for the changes,
and try and keep up, okay?
(ROCK 'N' ROLL MUSIC PLAYING)
Doc. Doc, come in!
Marty, come in.
Listen, Biff's guys
chased me into the gym,
and they're going to jump me.
Then get out of there!
No, Doc, not me.
The other me.
The one that's up on stage
playing Johnny B. Goode.
Great Scott!
Your other self will miss
the lightning bolt
at the clock tower,
you won't get back
to the future, and we'll
have a major paradox!
Wait, wait, wait.
A paradox?
You mean one of
those things that can
destroy the universe?
Precisely.
Marty, you have to stop
those guys at all costs,
but without being
seen by your other self
or your parents.
10-4.
What the hell?
Where is he?
Who?
Calvin Klein.
The guy with the hat,
where is he?
Oh. He went that way.
I think he took your wallet.
I think he took his wallet.
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Johnny B. Goode
Go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
Johnny B. Goode
(HEAVY METAL RIFFS PLAYING)
(FEEDBACK)
(HIGH-PITCH NOTE PLAYING)
(AMPLIFIERS HUMMING)
(SIGHS)
I guess you guys aren't
ready for that yet.
But your kids are
going to love it.
Hey, Doc, success.
Everything's cool.
DOC: Great. I'll be
landing at the school roof
in about one minute.
I'll be there.
Lorraine.
Marty, that was
very interesting music.
I hope you don't mind,
but George asked if
he could take me home.
Great. Lorraine, I had
a feeling about you two.
I have a feeling, too.
Hey, butthead!
You think that
stupid disguise
would get by me?
Let's have it out.
You and me, right now.
No, thanks.
What's the matter?
Where are you going?
Are you chicken?
That's it, isn't it?
Nothing but
a little chicken.
Nobody
calls me chicken.
What the hell?
You steal my stuff?
(GROANING)
And this one's
for my car!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Doc!
Doc! I blew it.
Biff nailed me.
He took the book.
He drove away
with it in his car.
It's my fault, Doc.
I should have got
out of there sooner.
No time for that now.
Which way did he go?
East towards
the River Road Tunnel.
Get in!
Yes!
There he is, Doc!
Let's land on him.
We'll cripple his car.
Marty, he's in a '46 Ford.
We're a DeLorean.
He'd rip through us
like we were tin foil.
So what do we do?
I have a plan.
MAN ON RADIO:
Repeating tonight's
earlier weather bulletin,
a severe thunderstorm is
heading for Hill Valley.
Serving Hill Valley
and all of Hill County,
you're tuned to KKHV,
the voice of Hill Valley.
Turning to
community calendar,
the Hill Valley
Women's Club bake sale
will be held
tomorrow afternoon
from 2:00 to 5:00
at the community center
on Forest Road.
For you sports fans
out there,
there was
a lot of action today
in college football.
Here's what happened
to the top 10.
UCLA narrowly
defeated Washington 19-17.
Michigan State
crushed Minnesota 42-14.
Ohio State
beat lowa 20-10.
Michigan
blanked Indiana 30-0.
Shit.
It was Notre Dame over
North Carolina, 27-7.
Son of a bitch.
Oklahoma ripped
lowa State 52-0.
West Virginia lost
to Pittsburgh 26-7.
Texas A&M over Rice 20-10.
Maryland
defeated Clemson 25-12,
and it was Texas
Christian over Texas 47-20.
Repeating tonight's
earlier weather bulletin,
a severe...
You again?
Give me that book.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Let it go!
Whoa!
Let go of the car!
(EXCLAIMS)
That'll teach him.
(GROANS)
(HORN HONKING)
(SCREAMING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(SCREECHING)
Oh!
(LAUGHING)
Go, Doc!
Hold on, Marty!
Shit!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(LAUGHS)
Yes!
(BIFF GROANING)
(SPITTING)
Manure!
I hate manure!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Doc, is everything
all right? Over.
DOC: 10-4, Marty,
but it's pretty miserable
flying weather.
Much too turbulent
to make a landing
from this direction.
I'll have to circle around
and make a long approach
from the south.
Have you got the book?
In my hand, Doc!
I got it in my hand!
Burn it!
Check!
Doc! Doc!
That newspaper changed.
Doc, my father's alive!
That means everything's
back to normal, right?
Mission accomplished.
That means Jennifer's okay
and Einie's okay, right?
That's right, Marty.
It's the ripple effect.
The future is back,
so let's go home.
Right. Let's get our
asses back to the...
Doc, Doc,
are you okay?
That was a close one, Marty.
I almost bought the farm.
Well, be careful.
You don't want to get
struck by lightning.
Doc.
Doc?
Doc, come in, Doc.
Doc, do you read me?
Do you read me, Doc?
Come in. Doc.
Oh, no.
He's gone.
The doc's gone.
Mr. McFly!
Huh?
Is your name
Marty McFly?
Yeah.
I've got something for you.
A letter.
A letter for me?
That's impossible.
Who the hell are you?
Western Union.
Actually, a bunch of us
at the office
were kind of hoping
maybe you could
shed some light
on the subject.
See, we've had that
envelope in our possession
for the past 70 years.
It was given to us
with the explicit
instructions
that it be delivered
to a young man
with your description
answering to
the name of Marty
at this exact location
at this exact minute,
November 12, 1955.
We have a little bet
going as to whether
this Marty would
actually be here.
Looks like I lost.
(LAUGHING)
Did you say 70 years?
Yeah, 70 years,
2 months, 12 days
to be exact.
Here sign on line 6,
please.
Here you are.
It's from the doc!
"Dear Marty,
if my calculations
are correct,
"you will receive this
letter immediately after
"you saw the DeLorean
struck by lightning.
"First, let me assure you
that I'm alive and well.
"I've been living happily
these past eight months
in the year 1885.
"The lightning bolt..."
1885!
"September, 1885."
Wait, wait, kid!
Wait a minute.
What's this all about?
He's alive!
The doc's alive!
He's in the Old West,
but he's alive.
Yeah, but, kid,
you all right?
Do you need any help?
There's only one man
who can help me.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SIGHS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHING)
Doc! Doc! Doc!
Doc! Doc!
What?
(SCREAMS)
Okay, relax, Doc.
It's me. It's me!
It's Marty.
No, it can't be.
I just sent you
back to the future.
Yeah. No, I know.
You did send me
back to the future,
but I'm back.
I'm back
from the future.
Great Scott!
Doc! Doc. Doc.
Fantastic.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Hey, McFly.
Just try it, Tannen!
Come on, runt!
You can dance
better than that!
(YELLING)
(HORN BLOWING)
(EXCLAIMING)